www.enhancv.com  Powered  by 
 OM KOTAWALA  
 
 
 
Education  
Vishwakarma  Government Engineering  College               BE in IT (CGPA : 8.78)             2022   -  2026 
RPTP  Science  School , Anand        HSC ( 86 %)    March - 2022  
I B Patel English  School, Anand      SSC ( 86 %)    March - 2020 
 
Projects  
 
Automobile  Spareparts  Purchasing  website                                              November(2024) û February(2025)  
ò The Automobile  Spare  parts  Purchasing  Website  is a smart  inventory  and sales  solution  designed  to streamline  the 
procurement, tracking, and  sales of vehicle spare parts. It ensures efficient stock management, order processing, and 
real-time availability updates for automotive components.  
ò Technologies used :  HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL(database).  
ò Role : UI Developer.  ò Team Size : 5 
Women  Safety  (SHEKavach)                                                                    September(2024) û November(2024)  
ò The Women  Safety Analytics System  is an AI-powered  real-time monitoring  solution  designed to  enhance  women's  
security  using computer  vision and  deep learning . It detects gender distribution, identifies lone women in unsafe  
conditions (12 AM - 5 AM), and  recognizes SOS  gestures to trigger instant alerts  and also stores the information of 
Emergency with time and location(L ongitude  and Latitude) in auditlogs . 
ò Technologies used :  Python, Keras , Pytorch, TenserFlow, OpenCV, MediaPipe, CNN . 
ò Role : Trained the Model . ò Team Size : 6 
 
HealthMate                                                                                                     January( 2025) û February(2025)  
ò HealthMate is an AI-driven medical chatbot designed to provide instant health guidance, symptom analysis, and 
preliminary medical advice . Using Natural Language Processing (NLP) and machine learning , it understands user 
queries and offers relevant health information.  
ò Technologies used :  Python, Keras , Pytorch, Langchain, Huggingface  model (Mistral 7B), HTML, JavaScript, CSS, 
MongoDB.  
ò Role : Chatbot Developer with UI.  ò Team Size : 6 
 
Skills  
 
 
ò Programming  Languages  : C, Java,  Python  
ò Web  Development  : HTML,  CSS,  JavaScript,  PHP,  Node.js  
ò Frameworks  & Libraries  : Bootstrap,  AngularJS  , ReactJS , ExpressJS  
ò Database Management  : MySQL  , MongoDB  
 
Key Achievements  
 
ò Finalist of Health Hack at VIT Bhopal   ò Top in zonal round for SIH 2024   
 
Co-Curricular  Activities  
 
 
 
ò Attended the workshop on Blockchain in September 2024.  
ò Attended the workshop on Java Script in July 2024.  
ò Completed the certified courses of HTML , CSS,  and Java Script.   
ò Got an Certificate on Hacker Rank for Basics of C language .  
Om Nivas, 80 Feet Road, Anand  
9898787134  
omkotawalaibpes@gmail.com  
https://github.com/om -kotawala  
https://www.linkedin.com/in/om -kotawala -35b760216/  
